# **Tanise Williams**

Software Engineer

Oakland, CA 94610 (917) 859-7077 tanwill.github.io tanise.williams@icloud.com

#### **ABOUT**

As a Software Engineer and Revenue Operations Consultant I am involved in the strategic convergence of technology, data, sales, marketing, and customer success to drive full funnel accountability across the client's revenue engine. I have years of experience with Apex, Java, JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest, Node, Salesforce, SQL, SOQL, Agile, Git, and other technologies. I am an analytical, solution driven thinker who prioritizes the advancement of client processes and systems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Go Nimbly,** San Francisco, CA — Software Engineer

July 2019 - PRESENT

- ◆ Revenue Operations Consultant / Full Stack Software Engineer (Apex/Java, React, and Redux).
- ◆ Salesforce Administration, Development, and API Integration.
- ♦ Go Nimbly is a San Francisco-based Revenue Operations industry leader and business stack consultancy. Go Nimbly provides SaaS and other innovative, high-growth companies with the strategies, technologies and operational roles needed to optimize strategic growth and meet the revenue goals of their C-suites and investors.

### **Ada's List,** San Jose, CA — *Member*

March 2020 - PRESENT

♦ Ada's List is a global community for women in tech, based on principles of inclusion, empowerment, and diversity. We're a group of 7500+ women who work in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics.

## **Women in Revenue,** London, England, United Kingdom — *Member*

March 2020 - PRESENT

♦ Women in Revenue is a non-profit organization focused on current and future women leaders in technology, sales, and marketing roles with education, support, and networking opportunities.

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Apex / Java JavaScript React Redux Jest Node.js Salesforce

#### **OPERATING SYSTEMS**

Macintosh Windows Linux iOS

#### **APPLICATIONS**

Google API, Google Docs, Photoshop, Atlassian Jira

#### **OTHER TECHNOLOGIES**

Git, Gulp, SQL, SOQL, Visual Studio Code, Vim

## **University of California, Berkeley,** Berkeley, CA — *Software Developer*

January 2019 - July 2019

- ◆ Position with a university affiliated digital agency from January 2019 to July 2019.
- ◆ Building pixel perfect, custom websites to high specifications for an array of clients and organizations, primarily UC Berkeley (haas.berkeley.edu, law.berkeley.edu).
- ◆ Ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs while optimizing applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- ◆ Assuring that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end.
- ♦ Handling asynchronous requests, partial page updates, AJAX calls, and the Fetch API.

June 2018 - December 2018

- ◆ Contract position with UC Berkeley Public Affairs from June 2018 to December 2018.
- ◆ Developed and modified codebases for University websites (berkeley.edu, news.berkeley.edu, calparents.berkeley.edu, blogs.berkeley.edu) in accordance with branding guidelines.
- ♦ Worked with campus leadership, journalists, and staff to design and implement needed technical features and functionalities.
- ◆ Customized 3rd party analytics software (Chartbeat) with JavaScript and PHP.
- ◆ Converted comprehensive layouts and wireframes into working, responsive features.
- ◆ Prioritized user experience and web accessibility.

## **Independent Contractor**, San Francisco, CA / New York, NY — Front End Developer

January 2016 - PRESENT

- ◆ Provided Front End development services for companies in San Francisco, CA and New York, NY.
- ◆ Analyzed detailed business requirements and provided recommendations for technical developments and implementations.
- ◆ Created and modified consumer-facing web applications by way of content management systems.
- ◆ Coordinated workflow processes while solving issues with object-oriented programming, testing, and cross-browser compatibility.

## **Lumina**, New York, NY — Front End Developer

DECEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2018

- ◆ Configured servers and imported/exported databases using Apache, PHP, and MySQL.
- ◆ Designed, developed, and built consumer-facing web applications using JavaScript, Node, React, PHP, and model-view-controller (MVC) architecture.
- ◆ Developed mobile-first web pages based on designs while prioritizing user-experience.
- ♦ Worked with project managers to complete tasks for clients using Agile methodology.
- ◆ Utilized Google Maps API to create custom forms for client websites.
- ◆ Initiated and implemented source control, team collaboration tools, and SEO best-practices.

## **The Berman Group,** New York, NY — Front End Developer

JANUARY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

- ◆ Executed daily email marketing using Photoshop, MailChimp, and Constant Contact.
- ◆ Started servers using Node.js and Bash scripts.
- ◆ Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.
- ◆ Maintained various client sites and web applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Udacity**, Mountain View, CA

AI for Business Leaders Executive Program

Issued: May 2020

Credential ID: 2DC9J5M2

Credential URL: https://confirm.udacity.com/2DC9J5M2

### **University of North Florida**, Jacksonville, FL

Undergraduate coursework towards Bachelor of Science (Psychology).

### **General Assembly,** New York, NY

JavaScript focused workshops and classes.